<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><extensionAttribute>
<displayName>Code42 - Last Connected</displayName>
<description>This attribute displays the last time CrashPlan established a connection with the server.  This attribute applies to both Mac and Windows.</description>
<dataType>date</dataType>
<scriptContentsMac>#!/bin/sh&#13;
&#13;
####################################################&#13;
### INFO ###&#13;
#Revamped by: Rhio&#13;
#Revamped on: August, 8th, 2020&#13;
#Display Name: Code42 - Last Connected&#13;
#Revamped again on: April 28th, 2022 by Jamie Piperberg&#13;
#Revamped because: python 2.7 was removed from macOS 12.3&#13;
#Description: This attribute displays the last time Code42 established a connection with the server. &#13;
#Data Type: Date&#13;
#Input Type: Script&#13;
####################################################&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
####################################################&#13;
### VARIABLES ###&#13;
&#13;
#use the server address utilized to log into a fresh client installed manual deployment&#13;
CP_ServerAddress="central.crashplan.com"&#13;
&#13;
#This port should work for everyone, it may be different if you have an on-prem install and have altered your ports from the default ports&#13;
CP_ServerPort="4285"&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
#Configure an API account with the minimum roles possible, for cloud customers, this would be an Org Admin or All Org Admin, and must be a LOCAL account within the console. If you are a cloud customer, this is also required to be a full email address.&#13;
CP_AdminUsername="support@code42.com"&#13;
&#13;
#If desired you could encrypt this with base 64 or a keypair stored in a separate file or config profile elsewhere on the machine to avoid having it in plaintext. Since you should have limited the rights of this account, the vulnerability should be reduced.&#13;
CP_AdminPassword=""&#13;
&#13;
####################################################&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
####################################################&#13;
### LOGIC ###&#13;
&#13;
if [ "$CP_ServerAddress" == "" ] || [ "$CP_ServerPort" == "" ] || [ "$CP_AdminUsername" == "" ] || [ "$CP_AdminPassword" == "" ];then&#13;
&#13;
	echo "Please ensure all variables are set in the extension attribute script."&#13;
&#13;
else&#13;
&#13;
	if [ -f /Library/Application\ Support/CrashPlan/.identity ];then&#13;
		&#13;
		#Checks the Unique Code42 Identifier to the currently running backup; the directory may need to be updated if they ever change the name of their cached settings directory&#13;
		GUID=`/bin/cat /Library/Application\ Support/CrashPlan/.identity | grep guid | sed s/guid\=//g`&#13;
		&#13;
		#Queries API of your Code42 instance then uses shell tools to parse the data&#13;
		#This will break if the vendor changes the JSON schema, but will work without bundling your own python or python3 on your endpoints&#13;
		#python3 code is python3 -c 'import json,sys;print( json.load(sys.stdin)["data"]["lastConnected"])' if you go that route&#13;
		#( replaces everything between the first and second | ) &#13;

		value=`/usr/bin/curl -u "$CP_AdminUsername":"$CP_AdminPassword" -k "https://"$CP_ServerAddress":"$CP_ServerPort"/api/Computer/"$GUID"?idType=guid" | awk -F"\"lastConnected\":\"" '{print $2}' | awk -F\" '{split($1,a,"."); print a[1]}'`&#13;
		&#13;
		#Converts the time format from the resulting JSON to the Jamf Smart Group compatible format &#13;
		result=`/bin/date -j -f "%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%S" "$value" "+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M:%S"`&#13;
		&#13;
		echo "&lt;result&gt;$result&lt;/result&gt;"&#13;
	&#13;
	else&#13;
	&#13;
		echo "&lt;result&gt;Not installed&lt;/result&gt;"&#13;
	&#13;
	fi&#13;
fi&#13;
####################################################</scriptContentsMac>
</extensionAttribute>
